The epic story of a world at war. And a boy at play.
Hope and Glory is a drama, war, family film directed by John Boorman.
A middle-aged man recalls his childhood growing up in
and around London during World War II.
Bill, played by Sebastian Rice-Edwards.
Sue, played by Geraldine Muir.
Grace, played by Sarah Miles.
Clive, played by David Hayman.
Dawn, played by Sammi Davis.
Mac, played by Derrick O'Connor.
Hope and Glory is a 1987 comedy-drama war film written, produced, and directed by John
Boorman based on his own experiences growing up in London during World War II.
It was distributed by Columbia Pictures.
The title is derived from the patriotic British song "Land of Hope and Glory".
The film tells the story of the Rohan family and their experiences, as seen
through the eyes of the son, Billy (Sebastian Rice-Edwards).
A critical and commercial success, the film won the Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy and received five
Academy Award nominations, including Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Original Screenplay (all for Boorman).
It also received 13 BAFTA Award nominations, winning for Best
Actress in a Supporting Role (Susan Wooldridge).
The film explores themes of london, england, wartime, based on
true story, semi autobiographical, home front.
The tone is emotional.